A Guide to the Papers of the Middle Atlantic Chapter of the American Rhododendron Society
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Middle Atlantic Chapter of the American Rhododendron Society 1951-1983
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10553
ca. 5,000 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This accession was deposited in the Library by the Middle Atlantic Chapter of the American Rhododendron Society through Mr. Harry L. Wise of Charlestown, West Virginia, on May 24, 1983. The collection was made a gift on April 8, 1988.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of ca. 5,000 items (9 Hollinger boxes, ca. 4 linear shelf feet), 1951-1983, records of the Mid-Atlantic Chapter of the American Rhododendron Society. Correspondence, minutes, and photographs pertaining to various activities of the chapter comprise the collection. A major portion of the records deals with the administration of the Mid-Atlantic Chapter, such as the election of officers, finances, and programs for annual meetings. The correspondence also pertains to the registration of new hybrids, seed exchange, research on rhododendrons, publications, and rhododendron gardens. Minutes and newsletters of various chapters from 1981 to 1983 are also present.
The American Rhododendron Society was founded in 1944 as an organization for amateur and professional growers of rhododendrons and azaleas. The organization conducts research, offers courses, compiles statistics, registers names of new clonal selections, and sponsors competitions. National meetings are held annually, usually in April or May.
Arrangement
The original order of the collection has been maintained, with some modifications. General correspondence files interspersed with separate files on meetings of the Middle Atlantic Chapter, as well as regional and national meetings of the American Rhododendron Society, comprise the bulk of the collection. Also included are minutes of the national organization. Material within all folders is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box Box 1)
- Financial Papers, 1952 September-1955 June (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1954 January-1956 May; 5 folders (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1956 June-December (Box Box 2)
- Bank Statements, 1956 March-1958 February (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1957 January-1958 December; 4 folders (Box Box 2)
- Transcript of midwinter meeting, Richmond, Va., 1958 January 25 (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence re midwinter meeting, Richmond, Va., 1958 January (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence re spring meeting, Norfolk, Va., April, 1958, 1958 February-April (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1959 January-December (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence re spring meeting, Asheville, North Carolina, June, 1959, 1959 February-1960 January (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence re spring meeting, Bethesda, Md., May, 1960, 1959 June-1960 June, n.d. (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence re spring meeting, Charlottesville, Va., April, 1961, 1959 Ju1.-1961 March (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence re spring meeting, Charlottesville, Va., April, 1961, 1961 April-September, n.d. (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1960 (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence re American Rhododendron Society 1962 Annual Meeting, Wilmington, Delaware, 1960 June-1961 December; 2 folders (Box Box 3)
- Correspondence re American Rhododendron Society 1962 Annual Meeting, Wilmington, Delaware, 1962 January-October, n.d.; 2 folders (Box Box 4)
- Correspondence, 1961 January-1962 December; 4 folders (Box Box 4)
- Correspondence re exhibition at American Rhododendron Society 1962 Annual Meeting, 1962 January-April (Box Box 4)
- Correspondence re spring meeting, Richmond, Va., May, 1963, 1962 November-1963 May, n.d.; 2 folders (Box Box 5)
- Correspondence, 1963 January-December; 2 folders (Box Box 5)
- Correspondence re spring meeting, Washington, D.C., May, 1964, 1963 June-1964 May, n.d.; 2 folders (Box Box 5)
- Correspondence, 1964 January-May (Box Box 5)
- Correspondence, 1964 June-1966 December; 6 folders (Box Box 6)
- Correspondence re spring meeting, Philadelphia, Pa., May, 1966, 1965 February-1966 June, n.d. (Box Box 6)
- Correspondence, 1967 January-April (Box Box 6)
- Correspondence, 1967 May-1968 December; 3 folders (Box Box 7)
- Correspondence re American Rhododendron Society 1969 Annual Meeting, 1968 August-1969 April (Box Box 7)
- Correspondence re panel discussion, American Rhododendron Society 1969 Annual Meeting, 1968 November-1969 April (Box Box 7)
- Correspondence, 1969 January-1969 December; 2 folders (Box Box 7)
- Correspondence re 1970 Eastern Regional Meeting, American Rhododendron Society, 1969 June-1970 Mar (Box Box 7)
- Correspondence re 1970 Eastern Regional Meeting, American Rhododendron Society, 1970 April-September (Box Box 8)
- Correspondence, 1970 January-1972; 6 folders (Box Box 8)
- Correspondence re spring meeting, Richmond, Va., May, 1972, 1972 February-May, n.d. (Box Box 8)
- Correspondence, 1973-1974-December; 3 folders (Box Box 9)
- Correspondence re spring meeting, Washington, D.C., May, 1974, 1973 June-1974 May, n.d. (Box Box 9)
- Minutes: American Rhododendron Society Board of Director's Meeting, 1981 April-1982 May (Box Box 9)
- Photographs, n.d. (Box Box 9)